<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>D-tacq Solutions</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/</link><description>Recent content on D-tacq Solutions</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/images/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/about/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="about-d-tacq"&gt;About D-TACQ&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ Solutions Ltd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a premier supplier of turnkey data acquisition products and services. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; specialises in high quality simultaneous digitisers, featuring high channel count, deep capture memory and open standard interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formed in 1999, we were initially active in supplying networked transient recorders based on ACQ32PCI to diagnostic applications in Plasma Fusion research. Since then we have supplied many hundreds of channels for high speed diagnostic experiments to research installations around the world, where our products&amp;rsquo; high channel density, simultaneous capture capability, Open Source software platform and value for money is appreciated. Plasma Fusion diagnostics are still a major market for &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, to which we&amp;rsquo;ve added support for innovative applications in Plasma Control and many other other market areas in research and test and measurement. The latest generation of products, capable of standalone networked operation, with further gains in channel density and reductions in cost per channel are opening up new market areas.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/architecture/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="architecture"&gt;Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; 4G digitizers use the Xilinx ZYNQ system on chip providing high performance at low cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; 2G digitizers conform to recognized industrial standards, and are designed to work in standard chassis. In common with most other digitizer cards, they can work as peripheral devices under the control of a system master computer in the chassis. New &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; 4G products are available both as discrete analog modules, available to plug into third party standards-compliant sites, and as 1U rack-mount appliances.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>CompactPCI</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/compact_pci/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/compact_pci/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="compactpci"&gt;CompactPCI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CompactPCI combines cost effective PCI bus technology with a conventional Eurocard form factor making it suitable for rugged and high I/O count systems. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s products bring high performance data acquisition to the &lt;tooltip&gt;6U&lt;/tooltip&gt; CompactPCI form factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large board area of &lt;tooltip&gt;6U&lt;/tooltip&gt; allows us to pack high channel density - up to 96 channels - together with high grade application specific signal conditioning on a mezzanine board into one slot. The long front panel edge allows easy signal connection from the plant via standard D-Types and Lemos, together with front panel external clock and trigger ports and clearly differentiated status LEDs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FMC/Modular</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/fmc_modular/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/fmc_modular/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fmcmodular"&gt;FMC/Modular&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; makes a large and increasing range of analog modules based on &lt;tooltip&gt;FMC&lt;/tooltip&gt;, a module standard that allows IO to connect directly to a &lt;tooltip&gt;FPGA&lt;/tooltip&gt; device with no additional bus layer, allowing efficient, low cost but high performance modules. A compatible carrier is required to operate the module. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; FMC modules fit compatible sites in both our own ACQ1001, ACQ2106 and third party carriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; carriers use a powerful System On Chip design based on the ZYNQ FPGA, that provides for the device interface, external interfaces on Ethernet and/or Fiber Optic with a embedded Linux-ARM system for supervision and control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FPGA</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/fpga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/fpga/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="fpga-capability"&gt;FPGA Capability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; cards use an advanced Field Programmable Gate Array FPGA for data marshalling. The configuration image for the &lt;tooltip&gt;FPGA&lt;/tooltip&gt; is held in local flash memory, allowing for easy in system upgrade. The devices used on the 2G series of cards have sufficient spare capacity to perform significant real time DSP on captured data in real time as it passes through the &lt;tooltip&gt;FPGA&lt;/tooltip&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; has implemented a range of standard DSP functions to ship with the data, including&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Intelligent Digitizers</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/intelligent_digitizers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/intelligent_digitizers/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="intelligent-digitizer-concept"&gt;Intelligent Digitizer Concept&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; digitizers feature an array of discrete &lt;tooltip&gt;ADC&lt;/tooltip&gt; devices, one convertor per channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This differs from most digitizer cards, which will use a single &lt;tooltip&gt;ADC&lt;/tooltip&gt; device with a multiplexer to route each channel in sequence onto the &lt;tooltip&gt;ADC&lt;/tooltip&gt; in turn. The &lt;tooltip&gt;ADC&lt;/tooltip&gt;-per-channel approach became cost-effective with the advent of fast and accurate integrated &lt;tooltip&gt;SAR&lt;/tooltip&gt; convertor devices, and offers the following advantages over the multiplexer approach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simultaneous Sampling - all convertors sample the data on the same clock edge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much Higher throughput.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inherently better crosstalk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suitable for Low Latency control applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D-TACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; digitizers also feature an on-board microprocessor and a deep DRAM memory buffer. The microprocessor is a low cost, low power device, but is able to give great flexibility in data and memory management.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Software</title><link>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sambelltacq.github.io/d-tacq.co.uk/software/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="we-support-open-standards-and-open-source-software"&gt;We support Open Standards and Open Source Software.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTACQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; policy to supply full documentation to all interfaces and the source code to working examples to customers on request. In addition, the majority of the operating software is made available to customers as source code under the &lt;tooltip&gt;GPL&lt;/tooltip&gt;. Where products are deployed with a host side driver, this driver is supplied for the user&amp;rsquo;s Linux host system as source code, licensed under the &lt;tooltip&gt;GPL&lt;/tooltip&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>